VANESSA CASTILHO DE CARVALHO



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-driven professional with career-long record of technical operations, graphic design, and UX/UI design success for a leading organization

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established responsive web design and design management paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Success-focused operator with expertise spanning operations optimization, relationship management, team leadership and collaboration, coding, A/B testing, user research, data analysis, storyboarding, prototype development, solutions development, wireframing, Agile Environment, website development, branding, and project management. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as quality assurance, client management, and extensive technical expertise.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Adobe Creative Suite
- Figma
- HTML/CSS
- Agile Environment

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BOATS GROUP, MIAMI, USA, MAY 2019 TO PRESENT

UX/UI DESIGNER

Boats Group is an advertising and software company for the marine industry with niche titles: YachtWorld, BoatTrader.com, and boats.com.

- Chart the design, coding (HTML, CSS, and JS), and administration of A/B Tests across YachtWorld, Boat Trader, and boats.com (combined 10 million monthly viewers) with a focus on increasing conversions, page views, and retention.
- Conduct extensive user research to transform inputs and behavioral data into design insights to enhance the portals.
- Lead the creation of storyboards, wireframes, user flows, prototypes, and site maps to effectively demonstrate interaction design concepts for the app and website. Closely collaborate with development teams in the implementation of designs.
- Partner with Product Managers to define and execute on overall project objectives, deliverables, and timelines.
- Serve as Lead Designer of a marketplace for each portal to display its services to be implemented in March 2020. Perform user research, evaluate user feedback, and implement solutions.
- Drive the development and integration of a Design System across the 3 portals with style guides and components for spacing, color, grids, shadows, typography, and imagery guidelines.

BOATS GROUP, MIAMI, USA, APRIL 2018 TO MAY 2019

WEB IMPLEMENTATION SPECIALIST

- Oversaw the delivery of over 45 fully responsive websites within a year in Agile/Scrum environment.
- Administered production and launch of new websites, as well as a coordinated pipeline of various staged projects. Closely communicated with developers, account management, and internal stakeholders.

- Effectively utilized HTML, CSS, and bootstrap to develop responsive websites and meet modern standards.
- Played a key role by executing branding, logo, and product redesign for website clients.
- Cooperated with Product Owner in the delivery of elegant and engaging designs to be applied to website products (templates) targeting UX/UI improvements.
- Liaised with internal and external design/dev resources to implement scalable front-end templates and design modules.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

GRAPHIC DESIGN, AUGUST 2010 TO AUGUST 2015 SENAC, Porto Alegre, Brasil

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Adobe XD Design & Prototype February to August 2019
- UX Research for Agile Teams August to November 2019
- UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, Development August to November 2018
- User Experience for Web Design February to June 2018

PORTFOLIO AND OTHER LINKS

- portfoliovanessa.com/
- linkedin.com/in/vanessa-carvalho-pillar
- github.com/vanessapyaar/myportfolio

Personal Project

LIFEMEDIA DESIGN, LIFEMEDIADESIGN.COM, OCTOBER 2018 TO PRESENT

• My freelance portal to provide designs and marketing materials for clients.

VOLUNTEERISM

Miami Rescue Mission, January 2019 to Present

I help prepare and serve meals to the homeless.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: English, Spanish, Portuguese. **Interests:** Scuba Diving, Sailing, Cooking.